Hello and welcome to Real easyy English in this podcast we have real conversations in easy English to help you learn I'm Becca and I'm Georgie
You can find a video version of this podcast with subtitles to help you learn on our website go to BBCclearningenglish.com. .
Hi Georgie hellello there how are you doing today I'm pretty good thank you how are you Good yeah I'm also pretty good but I forgot my lunch today No which is a bit annoying
But today we are actually talking about forgetting things and memory so it's a good topic it is for today's podcast
Yes and memory is your ability to remember things so Becca do you have a good memory I usually,
This morning not so much yes, I usually do have an all right memory, but it depends on what I'm trying to remember so.
I will remember experiences and people very well, but when it comes to tasks or things that I have to do for myself.
I must write them down or I will forget them I won't remember them I'm a very forgetful person I yes everyone knows me to.
Leave things in the house that I needed to bring or when I for example, anumbrella if I take that out it will get lost100% so I have a terrible
Memory so you don't have.
A great memory, Georgie, a memory we used to talk about the ability to remember something, but we can also refer to things from the past our memories from the past.
So do you have.
Any great memories I've got lots of good memories I think the best memory I have was when I was about eight years old I went
To a concert.
And I went to this concert with my dad, my best friend and her dad, and it was outside a summer's day, it was kind of sunset time.
We were both on our dad's shoulders singing, dancing, and she has the exact same memory, so I know that it's I know that it's real, it's not fake, didn't dream it, no, I didn't dream it.
But that's one of my favorite memories yeah, what about you I remember my first ever kind of live music
Concert experience as well.
It was around the time of November5th and here in the UK we often grew to see fireworks and it was the first time seeing fireworks.
So yeah, and also my first time like seeing a band play on a stage and yeah it was a great experience and that's
Probably why we remember these things because they do bring us.
So much happiness and joy when we talk about them Yeah exactly do you like to think about the past and memories I know some people don't like yeah
I I do I think.
It's really lovely to be able to remember, especially the good things from the past, how about you?
Yeah, I like to reminisce and reminisce means that we talk about things from the past, about memories with happiness, and that's really fun to do, especially with childhood friends.
When I meet up with friends from school, it's a lot of fun to kind of think about the good times from school and talk about people that we used to know.
Yeah, reminiscing is is a fun activity, yeah, I enjoy it too.
So we can talk about things from the past, but some people also like to keep things, collect things from the past mementos,
That's what those are called Do you like to keep mementos I love to keep.
Momentos, what kinds of things I, so I started a collection of fridge magnets from my first solo
Adventure and so.
You know, I get to see those little mementos every day and I'm reminded all of the places that I've been, it's nice to look at these mementos and then we reminisce yeah.
Let's recap the language that we learn in that conversation, starting with memory.
Memory is the ability to remember something, but we can also have memories and memories are things that we remember from the past.
For example, I have a lot of good memories from when I was a child.
We also heard forgetgetful which describes a person who does not have a very good memory I am a forgetful person If we reminisce about something, we talk about our memories from the past, memories that make us happy.
And we heard memento, which is an object which makes you think of a particular memory, place or event for example, I collect fridge magnets which are a memento of all of the places that I've travelled to.
And that's it for this episode of real easyy English we'll be back next week with another conversation in easyasy English and don't forget to test what you've learned with the worksheet on our
Website go tobbclearningenglish.com. .
And what would you like us to talk about on this podcast you can send us a question at learningningenglish@bbc.
Co.
Uk Bye for now goodbye.